sanindia.net 2017-11-21

# Privacy Policy | Sanindia.Net

### Privacy Policy

Thank you for visiting the Sanindia.net Web site (hereinafter “the Site” or “Sanindia.net”) and reviewing our Privacy Policy, effective March 06, 2008. Sanindia.net takes your privacy very seriously and is committed to safeguarding your privacy online. Please read the following policy to understand how your personal information will be treated as you make full use of our Site.

This Privacy Policy (hereinafter “Policy”) governs your use of Sanindia.net. This Policy describes the information we collect from you and what may happen to that information. For example, this Policy will let you know what information we collect from you; what cookies are and how they are used; how your information is used; who is collecting your information; with whom your information may be shared; what options are available to you regarding collection, use, and distribution of your information; how you may use other users’ information (“Users”); the types of security precautions in place to protect against loss, misuse, or alteration of your information; how Sanindia.net protects children’s privacy; and what else you should know about your online privacy.

Please note that we review our privacy practices from time to time, and that our practices are subject to change.  We ask that you bookmark and periodically review this page to ensure continuing familiarity with the most current version of our Privacy Policy.  All amended terms shall be automatically effective after they are posted on the Site.

By visiting the Site, you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy.  If you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use or access the Site.

The primary purpose of collecting information from you is to provide you with a safe, smooth, effective, and personalized experience.  We will only collect information about you that we consider necessary to achieve this purpose.

Generally, Sanindia.net collects personally identifiable information in two ways.  Some information is gathered when you order service from us.  This includes your name, address, phone number, fax number, email address, user name, and password.  Where possible, we indicate which fields are required and which fields are optional.  We also collect personal information when you report a problem with our services through the Site’s feedback form or contact email addresses.  If you contact Sanindia.net, we may keep a record of that correspondence.

Wherever Sanindia.net collects personal information we make an effort to include a link to this Privacy Policy on that page.

Data collection devices, such as “cookies,” are used to store, and sometimes track, information about you.  Generally, these cookies help provide personalized services and promote trust and safety.  A cookie is a small file containing a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and placed on your computer’s hard drive to assist us in providing our services.  All pages on the Site where you are prompted to login or that are customizable request that you accept cookies.  Cookies are only read by the server that placed them and are unable to execute any code or virus.  Most cookies are “session cookies,” and are automatically deleted from your hard drive at the end of a session.

More specifically, we use cookies to remind us of who you are and to access your account information in order to deliver to you a more personalized service.  This cookie is set when you register or “Sign In” and is modified when you “Sign Out” of our services.  We also use cookies to measure your visiting patterns in the aggregate.  We use this research to understand how our users’ habits are similar or different from one another so that we can make each new experience on Sanindia.net a better one.  We may also use this information to better personalize the content, banners, and promotions that you and other users will see on our Site.  Finally, cookies will allow you to enter your password less frequently during a session.  You are always free to decline our cookies if you wish and if your browser permits.

When your web browser requests a web page from another computer on the Internet, such as Sanindia.net, it automatically gives that computer the address where it should send the information. This is called your computer’s “IP address.” (IP stands for “Internet protocol.”) For many users accessing the Internet, the IP address will be different every time you log on.  We record the IP Addresses that access Sanindia.net along with related information such as your browser type and operating system. This information helps us, in part, learn about the geographical distribution of our website visitors and the technology they use to access our site so that we can improve our Site.

Sanindia.net uses your information to provide you with a customized website experience.  We also may use your personal information to manage and monitor your service orders and subscriptions with us; communicate with you via email; resolve disputes; troubleshoot problems; help promote safe interactions between Users; detect and protect against error, fraud, or other criminal activity; and enforce our Terms of Use Agreement.

When you are using the Site and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with Sanindia.net alone, unless we specifically state otherwise.  When you place an order using a credit card, your credit card information is sent directly to our processing vendor for payment processing.  Other than that, if data is being collected and/or maintained by any company other than Sanindia.net, you will be notified prior to the time of the data collection or transfer.

Please be advised that Sanindia.net advertisers or Web sites that have links on our Site may collect personally identifiable information about you.  The information practices of those Web sites linked to Sanindia.net are not covered by this privacy statement.

Generally, Sanindia.net will not disclose your personally identifiable information unless we have your permission or under special circumstances, such as those described below.

Third Party Data & Data in the Aggregate: Aggregate data (data gathered across all user accounts) may be gathered in a non-personally identifiable form to build higher quality, more useful online services by performing statistical analyses of the collective characteristics and behavior of our visitors, and by measuring demographics and interests regarding specific areas and services of the Site.  Aggregate data may be disclosed in a non-personally identifiable manner to advertisers and other third parties for their marketing and promotional purposes.  However, no personal information that could be used to identify you personally is disclosed in these situations.

External Service Providers: Separate services are offered by third parties, also known as external service providers, which assist us in providing our services.   In order to provide the services, where necessary we share information with our external service providers.

Business Transaction: Sanindia.net reserves the right to transfer any and all information that we collect from visitors, or that we otherwise collect concerning or in connection with the Site, to a third party in the event of a sale or other transfer of assets or of any portion of our business. In the event Sanindia.net enters a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information may be among the assets transferred.  You will be notified via email and prominent notice on our Web site for 30 days of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information.

We may disclose personally identifiable information where we have reason to believe that disclosing the information is necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal action against someone who may be violating Sanindia.net’s Terms of Use Agreement or may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) Sanindia.net’s rights or property, other Site users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities.  Sanindia.net may disclose or access account information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it and for administrative and other purposes that we deem necessary to maintain, service, and improve our services.

We cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personal information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Policy.  For example, we may be forced to disclose information to the government or third parties under certain circumstances, third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications, or users may abuse or misuse your personal information that they collect from the Site.  We use industry standard practices to protect your privacy, however, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information or private communications will always remain private.

You do not have to disclose personally identifiable information to view the Site.  If you choose to order our Services, you will need to disclose certain information as specified above.  Sanindia.net will send you email upon registration with and order submission through the Site.  Sanindia.net may also send you email regarding our products and services from time to time.  Only Sanindia.net, or agents working on behalf of Sanindia.net, will send you these emails.

Recognizing the global nature of the Internet, you agree to comply with all applicable local laws and rules regarding online conduct and privacy, as well as content.  Specifically, but not as a limitation, you agree to comply with all applicable laws regarding transmission of technical and personal data exported from the United States or the country in which you reside.

Finally, we do not tolerate spam.  You are not licensed to add a Sanindia.net’s user, even a user who contacted you, to your mail (email or physical mail) list without their express, written consent.

Your Sanindia.net account information is password protected so that only you have access to this personal information.  We recommend that you do not disclose your password to anyone.  Sanindia.net will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or unsolicited email.  If you choose to share your User Name and password or your personal information with third parties, you are responsible for all actions taken with your account and therefore you should review that third party’s privacy policy.  If you lose control of your password, you may lose substantial control over your personal information and may be subject to legally binding actions taken on your behalf.  Therefore, if your password has been compromised for any reason, you should immediately change your password.

Whenever Sanindia.net handles your personal information, we take steps to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with the relevant Terms of Use Agreement and this Policy.  We use procedural and mechanical safeguards to protect your personal information against loss or theft as well as unauthorized access and disclosure to protect your privacy, including encryption.  Unfortunately, however, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.  We cannot, therefore, warrant or ensure the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk.  Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.

Children under the age of 18 are not authorized to use the Site and we ask that children do not submit any personal information to us.  We do not share personal information about users under the age of 18 with third parties and we do not sell or rent personal information about any of our users, regardless of age.

Any questions regarding this statement should be directed to [ privacy@Sanindia.net](mailto:privacy@supersite.in?subject=Privacy%20Policy%20Page).

This Policy is the sole authorized statement of Sanindia.net’s practices with respect to the online collection of personally identifiable information and the usage of such information.  Any summaries of this Policy generated by third party software or otherwise shall have no legal effect, are in no way binding upon Sanindia.net, shall not be relied upon in substitute for this Policy, and neither supersede nor modify this Policy.

Please note that this Policy applies solely to our online information-gathering and dissemination practices in connection with the Site, and does not apply to any of our practices conducted offline.

End of “Privacy Policy” Page
